<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Victor De Grandis Site</title>
    <link>https://victordgrandis.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Victor De Grandis Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.128.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 17:35:23 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://victordgrandis.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to list Firebase Storage files in Golang</title>
      <link>https://victordgrandis.github.io/blog/posts/list-firebase-storage-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 17:35:23 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victordgrandis.github.io/blog/posts/list-firebase-storage-files/</guid>
      <description>Hi, today I want to share with you how I list all the files in certain folder of firebase storage and return them as an array. I this case only the files that are on the top level of that folder, and not the files inside a second folder.
Dependencies The package is &amp;ldquo;cloud.google.com/go/storage&amp;rdquo;. You can install it using go get cloud.google.com/go/storage
Why is this useful? I myself had the necessity of cleaning the storage folder of old files left there, so listing them is the first step.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Shareable PDF Reports with Kotlin and iText from RecyclerView Data</title>
      <link>https://victordgrandis.github.io/blog/posts/pdf-kotlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 13:00:23 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victordgrandis.github.io/blog/posts/pdf-kotlin/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Tables are a cornerstone of data presentation in mobile apps. Android&amp;rsquo;s RecyclerView makes it easy to create dynamic tables with large datasets. However, exporting this data to a PDF or other file format for sharing can be challenging. This post will address this challenge by showing you how to leverage Kotlin and iText to automate the creation and sharing of reports from your RecyclerView data, ensuring proper formatting for A4 pages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering React Query in Next.js</title>
      <link>https://victordgrandis.github.io/blog/posts/react-query/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 13:04:27 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victordgrandis.github.io/blog/posts/react-query/</guid>
      <description>React query is a tool for creating hooks for fetching, caching and updating asynchronous data repository.
Motivation Fetching data from your backend is one of the most performance killers features of any frontend, and it really helps to keep a copy of the fetched data in the browser, but it&amp;rsquo;s not always possible, or convenient to build a Redux store, so react-query is a good alternative for managing API results without having to do a lot of work for it, and without having to fetch it again every time you need it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use Hotjar JavaScript triggers on Angular</title>
      <link>https://victordgrandis.github.io/blog/posts/hotjar-angular/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 16:42:23 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victordgrandis.github.io/blog/posts/hotjar-angular/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript triggers are the most useful feature for using Hotjar HeatMaps in one page applications, because without that you can&amp;rsquo;t create HeatMaps on dynamic content or modals, dropdowns, etc. So i will show you how i made it work on an Angular project. I&amp;rsquo;m making the assumption that you already have an Hotjar account and initialize a project.
Include Hotjar in your project First we need to include the tracking code in our index.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
